Guide to the People’s Coalition for Peace and Justice Records TAM.058
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
People's Coalition for Peace and Justice Records
1970-1972
TAM.058
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.75 linear feet in two manuscript boxes.
The People's Coalition for Peace and Justice opposed United States involvement in the Vietnam War. The collection contains minutes, press releases and various internal documents.
People's Coalition for Peace and Justice.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
George Vickers sent a gift of the files of the People's Coalition for Peace and Justice and related organizations in August 1972. The accession number associated with this gift is 1974.006.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The People's Coalition for Peace and Justice was formed in 1970. It was a multi-issue coalition including various radicals (but not Trotskyists) and pacifists. It primarily opposed United States involvement in the Vietnam War but also supported struggles for civil rights and liberties.
Scope and Content Note
The records contain minutes, committee and conference reports, press releases, position papers, resolutions, leaflets and memoranda relating to the coalition's activities, mostly after 1971. Includes training manuals for the May 1971 activities in Washington resulting in over 1000 arrests; and photocopies of two letters by Sidney Peck and George Vickers tracing their involvement in the antiwar movement.
Arrangement
The folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Container list
Peck, Sidney R.; People's Coalition for Peace and Justice.; Vickers, George.; Minutes.; Press releases.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements |z United States.
- Container list
  - Childrens March for Survival, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clergy and Laymen Concerned Conference, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Emergency Washington Action, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fall, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fall Offensive, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Interfaith Campaign to Set the Date, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - May Day, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miami Conventions Coalition, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - National Action Group; Bradford Lyttle, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - National Coalition Conference, Chicago, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - National Coordinating Committee Meetings, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - National Coordinating Committee Meetings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Peace and Justice Conference, Milwaukee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - People’s Peace Treaty, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - National Welfare Rights Organization, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pacific Northwest Regional Conference, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Peck, Sidney R., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pentagon Blockade; People’s Lobby, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Releases, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - San Diego Convention Coalition, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - San Jose, Ca.: National Protest Against Repression, Racism & War, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Spring Offensive, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Spring Offensive, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Steering Committee Meetings, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vickers, George, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)